

Matt Evans

Auckland, New Zealand +64 27 777 1455 – mattevansnz@gmail.com www.mattevans.co.nz

Summary

I have relocated back to Auckland after eight years across Melbourne and London. I have more than 10 years experience developing and maintaining scalable web and mobile applications. I've had the pleasure of working with a mix of companies and varying projects, from startups to large corporations and government organisations. With each role, I've had input to varying aspects of the project(s) life cycle. I'm a stickler for detail, love working with people and enjoying seeing a project through from start to finish.

Experience

Populate Ltd. Lead Backend Engineer - May 2016 - Current

I'm currently leading development on Populate, a start-up focused on HR/headcount planning and analysis. This involves road-map feature planning and implementation. A strong technical role, challenges include complete end-to-end encryption and the technical implications and the overhead that comes with reading, writing and analysing locked data. As well as development, I'm responsible for our various build/CI pipelines, system architecture and our autonomous container based deployment (AWS). In recent months, I've also been covering a front-end resource and getting my hands dirty with our Angular stack.

Saatchi & Saatchi Head of Development – London & New York - Jan 2016 – May 2016

Saatchi & Saatchi Senior Developer - Sept 2014 – Dec 2015

My time at Saatchi has been spread across multiple campaigns providing technical advice, mentoring, management and implementation of large-scale web and mobile applications. This included architecture and development work on an AI robot, a heavily trafficked mobile application for T-Mobile and large corporate web applications. I also proposed, planned and developed a custom built continuous integration platform for the development team here. A largely backend focused role the skills employed include technical system design, development and implementation backed by AWS (EC2, S3, ELB, EBS, RDS, Cloudfront) and RedHat Openshift.

SitePoint Group / Wave Digital Lead Developer - Sept 2009 – July 2014

Wave Digital is a tech focused digital agency. Wave specialized in working with large complex problems and datasets to produce web and mobile apps for many blue chip corporate and government clients. Many projects were bespoke applications developed in a range of languages from Objective-C to Ruby on Rails. Wave is part of the SitePoint Group – responsible for 99designs.com, flippa.com, learnable.com and sitepoint.com.

My role entailed leading the development and project delivery of technical platforms (mobile and web) for many high trafficked applications. A variety of disciplines ranging from frontend development through to technical system design, backend development and implementation on AWS (EC2, EBS, RDS, ELB, S3, Cloudfront, ElasticSearch).



National College of Design & Technology Head of Department – Web Development & Interactive Design - Sept 2007 – Sept 2009

Natcoll is a polytechnic with three campuses nationwide, based in New Zealand. The school teaches a Diploma of Web Development of which I managed and mentored a team of lecturers as head of department, providing technical advice, coaching, curriculum development and scheduling. The role required me to keep my skills current/fresh, ensuring all technologies; languages, frameworks and libraries were investigated and used in the curriculum if applicable. This role relied on excellent technical and communication skills.

Skills

- Go, Ruby, Objective-C, PHP, JavaScript, Angular, MySQL, PostgreSQL, HTML/SCSS/LESS
- docker, nginx, Apache, Varnish, Squid, AWS, OpenShift, IA, System Design
- Vagrant, TDD, BDD, CI, Capistrano, Cucumber, iMeter
- Design/development of web, mobile and native iOS application architecture
- Linux cloud deployment and administrations
- Scalable web and mobile applications
- Knowledge and use of many open source libraries, packages and frameworks
- SVN, Mercurial and Git SCM
- Product and client management and strong communication skills
- Technical lead on projects

Please visit www.mattevans.co.nz for a detailed overview of a range of projects I have worked on.

Referrees

Matt is truly one of the best developers I have had the pleasure of working with over the last few years. He understands problems, can translate them into a technical brief and then gets his head down to solve them. He is adaptable and seems happy coding in anything from Objective C, to PHP, JavaScript and even CSS when the need arises. A great asset to any team.

Rob Thompson – Technical Director Saatchi & Saatchi – London/New York

Matt should be any good employers first pick for employee. He has fantastic tech skills across a very broad tech stack. Whatever the problem or job you have to throw at Matt he will dive in headfirst and do an amazing job. He can code, he can manage servers, he can deal with clients, he's great to hang out with - he's quite literally the full package both inside and outside work. I couldn't recommend him more highly and would hire him back without hesitation.

Guy Cooper – Managing Director Wave Digital

Matt was an outstanding employee and a key staff member of Wave Digital. He had a unique skillset as a highly technical developer who could break down complex terms for clients and explain the requirements in their language. He was always willing to go the extra mile, and is a stickler for best practice. I'm very jealous of whoever hires him next.

Ciaran Ryan – Commercial Manager SitePoint Group/Wave Digital



Matt is one of the most talented dedicated developers I have ever come across. He is always only too happy to help in any questions of problems and was an exceedingly good mentor to lower level developers. Matt's speed and efficiency in coding is second to none and it was a pleasure to work with him in many past projects.

Simon Lockyer – Lead Frontend Developer Saatchi & Saatchi - London

Education

- Dip. Web Development Yoobee School of Design & Development - Level 6
- Dip. Interactive Design
 Yoobee School of Design & Development Level 6
- Dip. Computer Graphic Design (Advanced)
 Yoobee School of Design & Development Level 7
- National Certificate in Adult Education and Training (Level 4) New Zealand Environment Open Polytechnic of New Zealand
- 10+ years industry experience with agencies and technical startups.